准备好了吗  孩子们
Are you ready, kids?
好了船长
Aye aye, captain
我听不见
I can't hear you
好了船长
Aye aye, captain
是谁住在深海的大菠萝里
Who lives in a pineapple under the sea?
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
方方黄黄伸缩自如
Absorbent and yellow and porous is he
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
如果四处探险是你的愿望
If nautical nonsense be something you wish
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
那就敲敲甲板让大鱼开路
Then drop on the deck and flop like a fish
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
准备
Ready
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
十字辣坚果
编剧
翻译: 1440kHz
分镜总监
指导总监
动画总监
统筹
监制
本字幕仅限学习交流
严禁用于商业用途
蟹堡王
你好  珊迪小姐
Bonjour, Mademoiselle Sandy
我给你带来了老样子
I have brought your usual
一份蟹堡套餐
one Krusty Kombo
谢了  海绵宝宝
Thanks, SpongeBob
不过吃的就用不着你给了
But I won't be needing the food
我自己从老家带了点东西
I brought a little something of my own from home
从老家
From home
珊迪的熏烤坚果
Sandy's smokin' barbecue nuts
我什么都没看见
I see nothing
外带食品不得进入蟹堡王
There is no outside food allowed at the Krusty Krab
没事  海绵宝宝
Come on, SpongeBob
你不说出来  坚果秘密就不会暴露了
I won't spill the nuts if you won't
完美
Perfecto
我什么都没看到
I haven't seen a thing
来尝一个
Try one
这才叫做火辣德州
Now that's what I call Texas heat
不过咱真得趁蟹老板没发现赶快停手
But we really should stop before Mr. Krabs finds out
发现什么
Finds out what?
蟹老板好
Hi, Mr. Krabs
外带食品
Outside food
求你网开一面  蟹老板
Mercy, Mr. Krabs
她不知道她那样是在犯错
She knows not the error of her ways
真是的
Please
只要你尝一口坚果
I bet one taste of these nuts
包你会改口的
and you'll whistle a different tune
都够了
That's enough
我要没收未经允许擅自带入的橡子
I'm confiscerating these unauthorized acorns
这擅自带进来的坚果哪里好了
What's so good about these unauthorized nuts anyway?
好啊
All right
珊迪  你被录用了
Sandy, you're hired
要干什么
To do what?
当然是在蟹堡王做坚果出来啊
Why, to make those nuts at me restaurant, of course
可好吃了
They're delicirous
你要是真觉得我会应聘这工作
You're a few pickles shy of a Krabby Patty
那你就想太多了
if you think I'm looking for a job
珊迪  这可不单单是工作
Sandy, this is no mere job
这是使命召唤
This is a calling
这是应尽的义务
This is a duty to serve
这是成真的美梦
This is a dream come true
好啊
Well, shoot
干就干
Why not?
不过我需要个烧烤架
But I'll need me a barbecue grill
没问题
No problem
我有个海军老妙计
I got an old Navy trick
可以临时做烧烤
for makeshift barbecues
哒哒
Ta-da
不算太破烂
Not too shabby
倒是可以用
I reckon she'll do
一定要把珊迪调教好  小子
Make sure to show her the ropes, boy-o
每日特餐  烤坚果
烤坚果
Barbecue nuts?
客人倒是什么都能吃了
These customers will eat anything
回味无穷
Nice aftertaste
珊迪和海绵宝宝在厨房里
Sandy's in the kitchen with SpongeBob
我们两个都在厨房里
We're in the kitchen, we two
珊迪和海绵宝宝在厨房里
Sandy's in the kitchen with SpongeBob
烤架上面烤坚果
Makin' nuts on the barbecue
听见蟹老板说的话了吧
You heard the boss man
跟我说说要干什么
Tell me what's what
神奇的魔法就在这里展现
Well, this here is where the magic happens
烤架
the grill
只要能尊重这个神圣的空间
As long as the sacred space is respected
整间厨房都能一团和气
the kitchen will remain in perfect harmony
你放心
Not to worry
我们在这就像一根绳上的蚂蚱
We'll be like two crickets on a fiddle in here--
给
Here
把自己敲晕吧
Knock yourselves out, please
已经在烤了
Already on it
所以说我要烤多少坚果
So how many nuts should I fix up?
坚果
Nuts?
抱歉  珊迪
Sorry, Sandy
你一定是误会了
There must be a mistake
全都是蟹黄堡的单子
These are all for Krabby Patties
放心
Don't worry
我来宣传坚果
I'll get the word out
你好  海霸王
Howdy, Bubble Bass
你应该挺想来吃点美味新品吧
I reckon you're hankering for a delicious new dish
挺不想的
Certainly not
我每天都买一模一样的蟹黄堡
I procure the same patty every day
因为我有精炼
because I have a refined--
好有烟熏味
Such smoky sapidity
这什么东西
What is it?
珊迪的熏烤坚果
Sandy's smokin' barbecue nuts
很好吃  对不对
Pretty good, am I right?
不仅仅很好吃
Not just pretty good
还好到可以上
but good enough to go on
大屏幕
the big screen
来尝尝珊迪的熏烤坚果
超神    满分
"Try Sandy's smokin' barbecue nuts"
大家听见没
You hear that, everyone?
这位的屁股也爱坚果
This guy's butt loves those nuts
我要来点坚果
I'll take some nuts
他的屁股从来不会错
His butt's never wrong
我要来点
I want some
我也要
Me too
坚果
Nuts
好啊
Doggy
这样就对了
Now we're cookin'
好
Yeah
给
Here
坚果需求大增
Demand for nuts is up
所以得增加供应
So we're increasing supply
让开  小子
Make way, boy-o
那个  蟹老板
Well, gee, Mr. Krabs
你可能会害可怜的珊迪累垮的
I think you might be overwhelming poor Sandy
烧烤午餐高峰期到了
This here's the barbecue lunch rush
然后
And, uh
给
here
应该是有人想吃蟹黄堡
Somebody wants a Krabby Patty, I guess
动作快
Now giddyup
所有餐点都上了
All the orders are up
对
Yep
所有餐点
All of 'em
那份是我的
That one's mine
完美
Perfect
不会再摇了
No more wobble
蟹黄堡
Patty
你不喜欢新装修吗
Don't you love the new look?
我只是来这吃坚果的
I'm just here for the nuts
牛仔王坚果小屋
Kowboy Krab's Nut Shack?
牛仔王
坚果小屋
疯子才全来这吃坚果
It's full of nuts, all right
海绵宝宝  能不能把钳子递过来
SpongeBob, hand me them tongs over there, will ya?
我现在实在是忙得不得了
I'm busier than a six-legged horse in tap shoes
谢了  海绵宝宝
Thanks, SpongeBob
一定要呼吸
Must breathe
坚果自有黄金屋
There's gold in them there nuts
袋子里有什么  蟹老板
What's in the bags, Mr. Krabs?
这袋是下一轮烤坚果的点餐单
This here's the next round of barbecue nut orders
你帮我我帮你  互惠互利
Well, scratch my back and call me a cactus
那袋装的是什么
And what about that one?
这袋啊
This one?
装的都是没用的蟹黄堡
This one's full of useless Krabby Patties
已经是没人要了  全变垃圾了
Nobody really wants 'em, so they're garbage
天啊
Oh, my
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob
嗨  珊迪
Hi, Sandy
只是在烤我面包
Just toasting my buns
让开  小子
Move over, lad
你挡我倒垃圾的路了
You're blocking me trash
钱钱钱钱
Money, money, money, money
坚果坚果坚果
Nuts, nuts, nuts
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob?
你没事吧
Are you gonna be okay?
回去工作
Back to work
钱不会自己烤自己
That money won't barbecue itself
我就爱钱的清香
I love the smell of money
烟味比平常重一点
Little smokier than usual
好
Yeah
章鱼哥先生  拖什么东西
Mr. Squidward, what's the holdup?
去问问你的烧烤大厨好了
Why don't you ask your pitmaster?
她不烤坚果了
She stopped barbecuing nuts
她什么
She what?
陆地生物
Land dweller
你这是什么意思
What's the meaning of this?
坚果用光了
I'm plumb out of nuts
你用光什么了
You're plumb out of what?
抱歉了  牛仔王
Sorry, Kowboy Krabs
看来你赚钱只能另寻他法了
Looks like you have to find another way
to make your dough
大家再见
So long, folks
坚果树已经干枯了
The nut tree's done run dry
大家好
Howdy, y'all
要想买到珊迪的熏烤坚果
I don't reckon we can get
no Sandy's smokin' barbecue nuts
不能没有珊迪是吗
without no Sandy, can we?
对
No
暴动
Riot
各位
Hey, everybody
这桌子沾上了德州烟熏味
This table's got that smoky Texas tang
太迷人了
Fascinating
珊迪坚果的烟味
The smoke from Sandy's nuts
把蟹堡王的东西都腌入味了
has flavored everything in this restaurant
开吃
Chow time
不
No
住手
Stop it
我的蟹堡王
Me restaurant
不
No
味道好香啊
Say, that smells delicious
这个啊
Oh, this?
只是没用的陈年蟹黄堡罢了
It's just a useless old Krabby Patty
没有木刺的美食
A snack without splinters
太潮了
How novel
我们应该可以分点蟹黄堡吃吧
Perhaps we could partake in your patties?
我想来一点
I want some of those
上菜了
Orders up
好消息
Good news
垃圾堡现在涨价一倍
Trashy Patties are now double the price
你先别急
Not so fast
这些蟹黄堡应该是免费的
I reckon these patties are on the house
对吧  海绵宝宝
Right, SpongeBob?
看来大家今天都为坚果狂
I guess we all went a little nuts today
还是回味无穷
Still a nice aftertaste
海胆哥与败蜗子
翻译: 1440kHz
编剧
分镜总监
指导总监
动画总监
统筹
监制
本字幕仅限学习交流
严禁用于商业用途
动动脚来坐坐好
Move your feet and grab your seat
海胆哥与败蜗子秀  开播
It's "The Sir Urchin and Snail Fail Show"
开播了
It's on
不好意思
Excuse me
借过一下
Pardon me
不好意思
Excuse me
借过一下
Pardon me
不好意思
Excuse me
海胆哥与败蜗子秀
这里是  海胆哥与败蜗子秀
It's "The Sir Urchin and Snail Fail Show"
我好苦
Woe is me
得来人给我的无价艺术珍品掸个灰
My priceless works of art need to be dusted
败蜗子过来
Oh, Snail Fail
是的先生
Yes, sir
海胆哥先生
Sir Urchin, sir
给艺术品掸个灰
Dust my art
遵命  海胆哥先生
Very good, Sir Urchin, sir
掸的出神入化
You dust divinely
给背面也掸一下
Now dust the back
遵遵遵命  海胆哥先生
V-v-very good, Sir Urchin, sir
你可恶
Why, you
我哪有
What I do?
高雅高雅高雅
Dainty, dainty, dainty
你可恶
Why, you
我哪有
What I do?
你可恶
Why, you
我哪有
What I do?
你可恶
Why, you
你的确可恶
Why you, indeed
为何我们大家不可恶
Why not any of us?
倘若宇宙的本质就是随机性
If the nature of the universe is random
为何厄运就不愿平等降临在我们身上
would not misfortune find us all equally?
而现今确乎如此
And yet, it does not
也许你应该不再发问  你可恶
Perhaps you should stop asking, "Why you?"
而开始问  我为何可恶
and start asking, "Why me?"
那不是台词
That's not the line
你怎么不打我了
Why did you stop hitting me?
我想让观众明白
I want the audience to know
我是个真正的演员
that I am a real thespian
不单单是在台上装疯卖傻
and not just some bumbling buffoon
你想认认真真当演员吗
Well, you wanna be a serious actor?
没人拦你
Nobody's stopping you
马上下台
Exit stage left
我的荣幸
My pleasure
不干了
I quit
你可恶
Why, you--
请稍候
没开玩笑  派大星
It's no joke, Patrick
我们最爱的喜剧组合
Our favorite comedy team
直播一半就解散了
just broke up on live TV
动动脚来坐坐好
Move your feet and grab your seat
海胆哥与败蜗子秀  开播
It's "The Sir Urchin and Snail Fail Show"
派大星  身为铁粉
Patrick, as devoted fans
我们必须说服两位偶像
it's our duty to convince our two idols
重聚复出
to get back together
喜剧界的未来寄托于此
The future of comedy depends on it
我加入
I'm in
得先分开才行
We'll have to split up
我才刚躺舒服呢
I was just getting comfy
我去找败蜗子
I'll go find Snail Fail
你去找海胆哥
and you track down Sir Urchin
祝你好运
Good luck
好耶
Booyah
出租船
Taxi
请问你要去哪
Where to, Mac?
带我去海胆哥家
Take me to Sir Urchin's house
海胆哥
Sir Urchin?
对  海胆哥
Yeah, Sir Urchin
那位老是会说
You know, the guy that goes
你可恶
"Why, you"
他可搞笑了
He's so funny
你是说这样的吗
You mean like this?
你可恶
Why, you
我就是海胆哥
I'm Sir Urchin
海胆哥
Sir Urchin?
你为什么来开出租船了
Why are you driving a taxi?
我跟我搭档五分钟前闹掰了
My partner and I broke up five minutes ago
打那以后  日子便变得难过起来了
and since then, times have been tough
你们之前可搞笑了
You guys were so funny back then
我哪有
What I do?
话说  你想不想
Say, Mac, how would you like
来当败蜗子二代
to be Snail Fail the Second?
真的吗
Would I?
这是什么
What is this?
可能是粉丝送给我的礼物
Probably a gift from one of my adoring fans
很接近了
Close
我就是粉丝
I am an adoring fan
抱歉  败蜗子先生
I'm sorry, Mr. Snail Fail
我只想问一下
I just wanted to ask
你跟海胆哥能不能重聚复出
if you and Sir Urchin could get back together again
就是  为了你们的粉丝
You know, for your adoring fans
我再也不演低俗喜剧了
No more low comedy for me
我若是想再度踏上舞台
The only way I shall ever step on a stage again
就必须成为正剧演员
is as a serious dramatic actor
请你离开
Now, be gone
我知道有家舞台
I know a stage
那边的观众会想看你表演
where people would love to see you act
真的吗
Really?
荫凉滩疗养院
可怜的鲭鱼啊
Alas, poor Mackerel
我认得他  比目鱼
I knew him, Halibut
一位爱打趣的
A fellow of infinite jest
他带领我指引方向上千次
He hath borne me on his fishtail a thousand times
垃圾
You stink
也许应该叫海胆哥过来
Maybe we should call Sir Urchin
不行
Never
你可恶
Why, you
我哪有
What I do?
你可恶
Why, you
我哪有
What I do?
你可恶
Why, you
我哪有
What I do?
你可恶
Why, you
俺哪有
What me do?
你可恶
Why, you
俺哪有
What me do?
为什么没人笑
How come nobody's laughing?
你说的是  俺哪有
Well, you're saying, "What me do?"
不是  我哪有
instead of, "What I do?"
大概就这原因
Maybe that's it
好提醒
Good note
明白
Got it
你可恶
Why, you
我哪去
Where I go?
这样还不行
Nah, that's not it
我们能有真正可以表演的舞台就好了
If only we had a real stage to perform on
我能有真正可以表演的舞台就好了
If only I had a real stage to act on
号外  号外
Extry, extry
才艺秀
裤头村才艺大秀今晚开演
Big Bikini Bottom Talent Show tonight
真正舞台秀
on a real stage
等了好久的机会可能要来了
This might be the break we've been waiting for
我闻到了重聚的气息
I smell a reunion
才艺秀
欢迎来到裤头村才艺秀
Welcome to the Bikini Bottom Talent show
裤头村才艺秀
尽情欣赏吧  裤头村
Take it away, Bikini Bottom
看看台下的观众
Look at all those people
不好意思
Excuse me
这条是演才艺秀的队伍吗
Is this the line for the talent show?
是你
You
你
成功了
Success
能看到你们重聚真是太好了
It's great to see you guys back together again
我绝对不跟在这位二流子后面上台
I am not following this riffraff onto the stage
我们先上台
We shall go first
走开  莎士比哑
Shove off, Fakespeare
我跟我新搭档派大星才是先来的
Me and my new partner, Patrick, were here first
那单片眼睛可贵了
That monocle was priceless
现在变垃圾了
Now it's garbage
你可恶
Why, you
我哪有要遭受这般命运的理由
What did I do to deserve this fate?
你可恶
Why, you
我何曾有
What have I done?
你可恶
Why, you
它哪有
What is it?
你可恶
Why, you
你是在说我吗
Are you referring to me?
你可恶
Why, you
我哪有
What I do?
原先的演法就很完美了
Our act was perfect the way it was
我不应该换掉的
I should never have tried to change it
败蜗子  老兄弟
Snail Fail, old buddy
请吧
go ahead
在我们的节目里加点严肃表演
Add some serious acting to our show
我只想让我们重聚复出
I just want to get back together again
我也是
So do I
你可恶
Why, you
我哪有
What I do?
我们可恶
Why, us
看我们哪有
Look what we do'd
你可恶
Why, you
一周后
可怜的鲭鱼啊
Alas, poor Mackerel
我认得他  海胆哥
I knew him, Sir Urchin
一位爱打趣的
A fellow of infinite jest
四处探险是他的愿望
nautical nonsense be something he wished
你的笑料何在  老朋友
Where be your jokes now, old friend?
是否还能让我笑
That I may laugh
开怀
With merriment?
你可恶
Why, you
我何有
What hath I done?
他们回归了  比以前更搞笑了
They're back and funnier than ever
感谢大家
Thank you, everyone
我们想花一点时间
We would just like to take a moment
进行大家所说的公开致意
to give a shout-out, as the kids say
感谢我们的朋友
to our friends
海绵宝宝和派大星
SpongeBob and Patrick
没有你们  我们绝对没法重聚复出
We couldn't have gotten back together without you guys
你们可恶
Why, you
我们哪有
What we do?
你们可恶
Why, you
又来了
Not again
本集完